[Music]
happy 8th
42 on a sunday morning everybody welcome
back to the channel this ice cream is
one that i've never tried can't see it
can't buy it it is marshmallow sky
that's a ben jerry's
flavor
that is only available in north america
as far as i can tell what is it it's a
marshmallow ice cream with
marshmallow swirls chocolate cookie
dough and double chocolate cookie dough
you can't buy it in pint tubs over there
either
it looks incredibly popular over there
we're gonna have a go and try and make
it and see but one thing i want to
mention before we start
is that ben and jerry's
have no marshmallow in their marshmallow
ice cream at all and as ben and jerry's
version doesn't have any physical
marshmallow in it they use
pectin
to create the same kind of texture that
the gelatin would in normal marshmallows
a couple of options to do this we could
use pectin
but we're gonna use actual real
marshmallows
so stick around and we'll show you how
to make it
[Music]
so this is a big old recipe so we're
gonna get straight in with the cookie
doughs first
these are modified versions of salt and
straws cookie doughs as they're just
really good
start by heat treating your flour in
your oven at 180 c for 10 minutes
make sure you do enough for both batches
and then let it cool for 15 minutes and
when you sieve it after make sure you
don't use a plastic sieve like me
[Music]
then in a bowl combine 60 grams of
softened butter along with 45 grams of
table sugar and 40 grams of brown sugar
then add half a teaspoon of salt and mix
it all in well
then add one tablespoon of corn syrup or
golden syrup
one teaspoon of vanilla extract and two
tablespoons of heavy cream or double
cream depending on what it's called in
your area of the world
once that's combined add the 70 grams of
your heat treated all-purpose or plain
flour and mix it in well finally add in
the chocolate chips and put it in a
container and freeze it
now the double chocolate cookie dough is
made in exactly the same way but you
remove 20 grams of the flour and replace
it with 20 grams of cocoa powder once
both cookie doughs are in the freezer
let's get on and make the ice cream base
the ice cream base will start as normal
by adding 400 milliliters of 2 milk to a
pan and add 65 grams of table sugar and
65 grams of dextrose if you don't have
dextrose just use 130 grams of table
sugar
then chop up 75 grams of gelatin based
marshmallows and let them melt in
decant into a container and then add in
250 milliliters of double or heavy cream
then as that's cooled down enough
straight away add one and a half
teaspoons of vanilla extract
now we're going to get our spirulina out
and this is one of the main selling
points for this ice cream ben and
jerry's used blue spirulina to colour it
and that's what we're going to do
so to use this add half a teaspoon of
the spirulina powder into one teaspoon
of water
mix it well and add it into your ice
cream base stirring it finally adding
your skimmed milk powder
put the whole lot covered into your
fridge
finally we're going to make the
marshmallow swirl i've used this quite a
bit and it's not marshmallow technically
it's meringue but it's what they use
add to a bowl two egg whites and a
hundred grams of table sugar and quarter
of a teaspoon of cream from tartar heat
it to 70 degrees over bain marie whilst
mixing constantly then remove it from
the heat and get your hand mixer out and
go to town for about five minutes on max
speed until you're left with something
that looks like this
you can store this in the fridge covered
for a good few days but it never lasts
that long in our house
now we're going to chop up our cookie
doughs into small cubes and put them
straight back in the freezer
[Music]
now that the base is totally chilled out
man we're going to put it in our ice
cream machine it's a decent sized batch
so we're going to use the lilo 5030 i've
brought the marshmallow swirl out of the
fridge to soften up just a little bit
while it's churning
and then when it's ready start loading
your tub with ice cream
cookie doughs marshmallow swells and
even though this has taken 75 years to
make you're still gonna need to freeze
it for a few hours before it's ready to
eat
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
so
quick snapshot of the shorts i'm wearing
look at that tub look
all the sun rays behind marshmallow sky
this is actually how they display it on
their website so
let's uh let's get some scooped up
[Music]
first off
look at that color i mean this is that's
that blue spirulina get green spirulina
and blue spirulina what is it it's a
microorganism
algae
that
gets it cut i don't know actually how it
gets its color so i was just going to
start no idea
what is spirulina it's a microorganism
that grows in lakes ponds and waterways
now it's slightly different to the green
spirulina the green stuff stinks of fish
but the blue doesn't smell like fish it
has a slightly weird smell but that
completely disappears when you make this
anyway so
loads of marshmallow swirl in there
loads of the two types of cookie dough
looks like the clouds are behind ben and
jerry's logo it's all good let's dive in
[Music]
the cookie doughs
are immense
like i said these are salt and straw
variations just slightly tweaked because
i used a recipe
that i also used in their salted malted
chocolate chip cookie dough
but i didn't want the malt flavor
so just adjusted those to suit this kind
of recipe so the texture's great
the ice cream itself it's a vanilla
flavored ice cream that's what it is
because they use
or they advertise that they use you know
the marshmallow ice cream but
marshmallows are vanilla flavored
for the majority so
they don't use marshmallows like i've
said they use pectin to create that kind
of texture
the pectin and gelatin will do the same
thing in ice creams they both absorb
certain amounts of water and give it a
little bit of a stretch but by melting
the marshmallows in here you get the
gelatin from the marshmallows you have
to account for the sugars that's what
we've done in a recipe here
the marshmallow swirl is perfect if you
use marshmallow fluff which you can do
it freezes just a little bit harder than
this this stays lovely and soft doesn't
matter how long you freeze it for so i
really recommend doing that marshmallow
it's marshmallow cream is what it is
what it's called in the us but
over here it's it's swiss meringue
i mean this is incredible you know it's
a really nice flavor if this is what it
tastes like in the shops you know i'd be
all up for going over there and buying
it but you know the whole plane ticket
thing just to buy ice cream i'm not sure
it works out financially viable but
hey
you only live once
so there you go marshmallow sky
i can't see this recipe on youtube
anywhere else so let me know if this is
an enjoyable recipe and one you want to
make
and thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like and subscribe and
we'll see you next week
[Music]